George Gaylord Simpson Papers 1918-1984 Mss.Ms.Coll.31
American Philosophical Society
- George Gaylord Simpson Papers
  - Series I. Correspondence, 1925-1984; 36 linear feet (Box 1-73)
    - United States Geological Survey (Report of Committee on the Geological Survey), 1954 (Box 67)
    - United States Geological Survey (Water Resources Division), 1955-56 (Box 67)
    - United States National Museum, 1931-36 (Box 67)
      Fort Union Fauna monograph
    - United States Post Office, 1944, 80 (Box 67)
    - University College London, 1978 (Box 67)
    - University of Denver, 1968-69 (Box 67)
      Wolfgang Yourgrau Memorial lecture
    - Upton, J. Duane, 1969 (Box 67)
    - Urey, Harold C., 1964 (Box 67)
    - Uribe, Veronica, 1983 (Box 67)
    - Urquhart, Jennifer, 1973 (Box 67)
    - Usher, J. Richardson, 1941 (Box 67)
      jobs in paleontology
    - Usinger, R.L., 1961, 66 (Box 67)
    - Utah State University, 1965 (Box 67)
    - Utgoff, Alexandra M., 1963 (Box 67)
    - Utrecht Micropaleontological Bulletins, 1975 (Box 67)
    - Uyeno, Teruya, 1979 (Box 67)
    - Vaccaro, Novelia, 1976 (Box 67)
    - Valentine, James W., 1972-73, 76, 78 (Box 67)
    - Vallance, Rhea, 1971 (Box 67)
    - Vallee, Jacques, 1963 (Box 67)
    - Vallejo-Freire, A., 1964 (Box 67)
    - Valverde, Felipe, 1971 (Box 67)
    - Valverde, Jose A., 1980-81 (Box 67)
    - Van Cleave, Harley J., 1947 (Box 67)
    - Van Couvering, John A., 1969 (Box 67)
    - Van Frank, Richard, 1953-54, 56, 73, 80 (Box 67)
    - Van Gelder, Richard G., 1962, 67-68, 80-81 (Box 67)
    - Van Hoepen, E.C.N., 1947, 66 (Box 67)
    - Van Houten, Franklyn B., 1939, 43, 47 (Box 67)
    - Van Husuly, V., 1957 (Box 67)
    - Van Niel, C.B., 1952 (Box 68)
    - Van Nostrand Company, Inc., 1968 (Box 68)
    - Van Stone, James W., 1978 (Box 68)
    - Van Straelen, Victor, 1937, 48 (Box 68)
    - Van Tyne, Josselyn, 1945-46 (Box 68)
      Wilson Bulletin
    - Van Valen, Leigh, 1957-66, 69, 74, 76, 78, 82-83 (Box 68)
    - Van Vark, G.N., 1971 (Box 68)
    - Van de Velde, R.W., 1962-63 (Box 68)
    - Van der Klaauw, C.J., 1951 (Box 68)
    - Van der Vecht, J., 1960 (Box 68)
    - Van der Voo, Rob, 1982 (Box 68)
    - Vancea, Stefan, 1964 (Box 68)
    - Vandebroek, G., 1959, 61-62 (Box 68)
    - Vander Hoof, V.L., 1934, 39-40, 42, 46, 52 (Box 68)
    - Vashisht, R.N., 1979 (Box 68)
    - Vassar College, 1956, 60-61, 64 (Box 68)
    - Vaughan, Elizabeth, 1944 (Box 68)
    - Vaughan, Peter P., 1967, 70 (Box 68)
    - Vaughan, Terry A., 1971, 73 (Box 68)
    - Veltri, Irma Matilde, 1975 (Box 68)
    - Venezuela (Government), 1940-42, 45-46 (Box 68)
    - Verhaeghe, Jan, 1977-78 (Box 68)
    - Verheyen, W.N., 1964 (Box 68)
    - Verlag Paul Parey, 1974 (Box 68)
    - Verville, George J., 1971 (Box 68)
    - Veterans Administration, 1960 (Box 68)
    - Vevers, H.G., 1973 (Box 68)
    - Vicencio A., Raul, 1964 (Box 68)
    - Victorian Studies (journal), 1974 (Box 68)
    - Viking Press, Inc., 1955, 63 (Box 68)
    - Villar, Jose Alvarez del, 1952 (Box 68)
    - Villarroel A., Carlos, 1973-75 (Box 68)
    - Villee, Claude A., 1945 (Box 68)
      Tempo and Mode
    - Vincent, John H., 1960 (Box 68)
    - Vinoly, J., 1958 (Box 68)
    - Virasore, Carlos A., 1981 (Box 68)
    - Viret, Jean, 1947 (Box 68)
    - Virginia, University of, 1957 (Box 68)
    - Visher, S.S., 1947-48 (Box 68)
    - Vishniac, Roman, 1960, 62-64 (Box 68)
      Living Biology film series
    - Vishniac, Wolf V., 1961, 63-64, 73 (Box 68)
    - Vivas, Eliseo, 1951 (Box 68)
      Julian Huxley's evolutionary ethics
    - Vogel, Nancy, 1959 (Box 68)
    - Vogel, W., 1969 (Box 68)
    - Vogt, William, 1941 (Box 68)
    - Vokes, H.E., 1941, 69 (Box 68)
    - Vorontsov, Nikolay N., 1967, 70-71, 83 (Box 68)
    - Vorzimmer, Peter J., 1974 (Box 68)
    - Vreeland, Frederick F., 1940 (Box 68)
    - Vuilleumier, Francois, 1972-74, 81-82 (Box 68)
    - Waage, Karl M., 1961, 82 (Box 68)
      Yale Peabody Museum, Director
    - Wace, N.M., 1967 (Box 68)
    - Wada, Kazuo, 1957-58 (Box 68)
    - Waddel, Virginia, 1982 (Box 68)
      Arizona State Retirement System
    - Waddington, C.H., 1952-53, 56, 59-60, 66 (Box 68)
    - Wagner Free Institute of Science, 1949 (Box 68)
    - Wahlert, John H., 1973-74 (Box 68)
    - Wake Forest College, 1961 (Box 68)
    - Wake, David B., 1980 (Box 68)
    - Wakefield, Eva Ingersoll, 1957 (Box 68)
    - Walcott, Charles, 1925, 63 (Box 68)
    - Wald, George, 1959, 64, 67 (Box 68)
    - Walker Press, Limited, 1972 (Box 68)
    - Walker, A.W., 1965 (Box 68)
    - Walker, Alan, 1967-70, 80 (Box 68)
    - Walker, John D., 1940, 44, 46 (Box 68)
    - Walker, Keir, 1953 (Box 68)
    - Walker, Roland, 1957 (Box 68)
    - Walker, Susan Watts, 1977 (Box 68)
    - Walkon, A.B., 1952 (Box 68)
    - Wallace, Steven M., 1976, 79 (Box 68)
    - Waller, Thomas R., 1980 (Box 68)
    - Walliser, O.H., 1979 (Box 68)
    - Walsh, Barbara, 1980 (Box 68)
    - Walsh, Margaret, 1968 (Box 68)
    - Walter, Donald O., 1958 (Box 68)
    - Walter, George T., 1966-67 (Box 68)
    - Walton, Dan W., 1964, 84 (Box 68)
      Factor Analysis in Mammalian Systematics
    - Wander, John M., 1979 (Box 68)
    - Wanderstock, J.J., 1949-51 (Box 68)
    - Wang, Ging-Hsi, 1950 (Box 68)
    - Ward, Angus I., 1935-36, 40-43, 47, 50 (Box 68)
      US Embassy, USSR
    - Ward, David, 1981 (Box 68)
    - Ward, Justus C., 1963 (Box 68)
    - Ward, Richard Carleton, 1967 (Box 68)
      Biophile Bulletin
    - Wardle, H. Newell, 1941 (Box 68)
    - Ware, Ali, 1979 (Box 69)
    - Ware, Caroline F., 1955, 58 (Box 69)
    - Warmoth, Arthur, 1967 (Box 69)
    - Warner, F.J., 1966, 69, 77 (Box 69)
    - Warner, Richard M., 1981 (Box 69)
    - Warren, Charles H., 1925-27, 35 (Box 69)
    - Warren, Edward R., 1936 (Box 69)
    - Warren, James W., 1962, 68 (Box 69)
    - Warren, Jim, 1970 (Box 69)
    - Warren, Lyman O., 1961, 63 (Box 69)
    - Warren, P.S., 1925 (Box 69)
    - Washburn, Bradford, 1970 (Box 69)
    - Washburn, Sherwood L., 1947-48, 62, 64-67, 72, 78, 80-81 (Box 69)
    - Washburne, Chester W., 1931 (Box 69)
    - Washington (Hotel), 1948-49 (Box 69)
    - Washington Academy of Science, 1940 (Box 69)
    - Washington Square Press, 1980-83 (Box 69)
    - Washington University School of Medicine, 1964-69 (Box 69)
      Terry Lecture
    - Washington, University of, 1952, 65-66 (Box 69)
    - Wassen, Henry, 1941 (Box 69)
    - Wasserburg, G.J., 1977 (Box 69)
    - Waterloo Lutheran University, 1972 (Box 69)
    - Waterman, Harriet C., 1949 (Box 69)
    - Waterman, Talbot H., 1968 (Box 69)
    - Watson, David Meredith Seares, 1937, 47, 51-52, 57 (Box 69)
    - Watson, George E., 1961, 71-72, 76 (Box 69)
    - Watson, James M., 1938 (Box 69)
    - Watt, Ward B., 1984 (Box 69)
    - Waverly Press, Inc., 1933, 35, 39 (Box 69)
    - Wayburn, Peggy, 1971 (Box 69)
    - Wayne State University, 1952, 65 (Box 69)
    - Wcau-TV, 1964 (Box 69)
    - Weaver, Albert B., 1981 (Box 69)
      University of Arizona, Exec. Vice President
    - Weaver, Warren, 1963, 66 (Box 69)
    - Webb, S. David, 1966, 68-69, 73, 75-76, 79-84 (Box 69)
      SVP Newsletter, editor
    - Webb, Walter N., 1964 (Box 69)
    - Weber, Cynthia, 1962 (Box 69)
    - Weber, Neal A., 1942 (Box 69)
    - Weber, R., 1926 (Box 69)
    - Webster, Douglas B., 1966, 68, 71 (Box 69)
    - Weddell, Alexander Milbourne, 1933 (Box 69)
    - Weeks, Albert L., 1974 (Box 69)
      Extraterrestrial life
    - Weg, Max, 1936 (Box 69)
    - Wegner, Richard W., 1939 (Box 69)
    - Weigard, Phil, 1983 (Box 69)
    - Weigelt, Johannes, 1935 (Box 69)
    - Weil, Laurie, 1962 (Box 69)
    - Weil, Susan F.C., n.d. (Box 69)
    - Weinberg, A. (Hartman-Weinberg), 1936 (Box 69)
    - Weinberg, Stanley L., 1960-62, 64, 68 (Box 69)
      Federation of Science Teachers Association
    - Weinberger, Bernhard W., 1926 (Box 69)
    - Weiner, J.S., 1963 (Box 69)
    - Weir, Barbara J., 1972-73 (Box 69)
      Zoological Society of London
    - Weishampel, Daivd B., 1975-76 (Box 69)
    - Weisinger, Herbert, 1959 (Box 69)
    - Weisser, Christian, 1971 (Box 69)
    - Weissleder, Wolfgang O., 1959 (Box 69)
    - Weitzel, Karl, 1934 (Box 69)
    - Welch, Barbara, 1967 (Box 69)
      Collier's Reference Service
    - Welch, M., 1941 (Box 69)
    - Welden, Arthur L., 1984 (Box 69)
      Biogeography of Mesoamerica
    - Weller, J. Marvin, 1950, 67 (Box 69)
    - Welles, Samuel P., 1947-48, 62, 64, 68 (Box 69)
    - Wellesley College, 1950 (Box 69)
    - Wells, John, 1960 (Box 69)
    - Welsh Pony Society of America, 1948 (Box 69)
    - Weltfish, Gene, 1939 (Box 69)
    - Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research, 1952, 59, 64, 67-68, 70, 74 (Box 69)
    - Werber, Robin, 1970 (Box 69)
    - Werbos, Paul J., 1966-67 (Box 69)
    - Werscheck, Barbara F., 1977, 79-80, 84 (Box 69)
    - Wescott, Roger W., 1960, 62 (Box 69)
      Darwinist Manifesto
    - Wesleyan University Press, 1964 (Box 69)
    - Wessler, Stanford, 1967 (Box 69)
    - West, George C., 1966 (Box 69)
    - West, Robert M., 1976, 79 (Box 69)
    - Westbrook Free Lectureship (Wagner Free Institute of Science), 1949-50 (Box 69)
      Program with abstracts
    - Western Ontario, University of, 1958 (Box 70)
    - Western Reserve University, 1965 (Box 70)
    - Westoll, T. Stanley, 1946-51, 53-59, 62, 67, 71, 75, 82 (Box 70)
    - Weston-Smith, Miranda, 1975 (Box 70)
    - Westphal, Frank, 1962 (Box 70)
    - Wetmore, Alexander, 1936-37, 46-47, 59 (Box 70)
    - Wettstein, Otto, 1934 (Box 70)
    - Wetzel, Ralph M., 1975 (Box 70)
    - Weyer, Edward, Jr., 1957 (Box 70)
    - Wgy radio, 1955 (Box 70)
    - Wharton, G.W., 1952 (Box 70)
    - Whatley, R.C., 1984 (Box 70)
      S.Am geological congress of 1970
    - Wheeler, G.C., 1941 (Box 70)
    - Wheeler, Lawrence, 1975 (Box 70)
    - Wheeler, Merritt I., 1937 (Box 70)
    - Wheeler, R.B., 1944 (Box 70)
    - Whelan, Sidney S., Jr., 1971 (Box 70)
      AMNH, Executive Secretary
    - Whistler, David P., 1984 (Box 70)
    - Whitaker, George O. and Doris, 1953, 56, 63, 66-67, 78-80, 82 (Box 70)
    - White, Charles F., 1934 (Box 70)
    - White, David, 1925 (Box 70)
    - White, David A., 1962 (Box 70)
    - White, Errol I., 1955-56, 62 (Box 70)
    - White, Harry (Mrs.), 1933 (Box 70)
    - White, John A., 1979 (Box 70)
    - White, John F., 1961 (Box 70)
    - White, Leslie A., 1950 (Box 70)
    - White, Max G., 1967 (Box 70)
    - White, Michael J.D., 1968 (Box 70)
    - White, Steven D., 1972-73 (Box 70)
    - White, Theodore E., 1941, 69 (Box 70)
    - White, Tim D., 1979 (Box 70)
    - White, William M., 1967 (Box 70)
      U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service
    - Whitehead, A.B., 1973 (Box 70)
    - Whitehouse, Frederick A., 1965 (Box 70)
    - Whiting, Frank T., Jr., 1971 (Box 70)
    - Whitlock, Herbert P., 1933, 35 (Box 70)
    - Whitmore, Frank Clifford, Jr., 1971, 73 (Box 70)
    - Whittier, John R., 1967 (Box 70)
    - Whittier, Sara, 1983 (Box 70)
      Washington Square Press
    - Whittington, Harold B., 1971 (Box 70)
    - Who's Who in American Education, 1941, 53 (Box 70)
    - Whyte, Lancelot Law, 1959-60, 63-65 (Box 70)
    - Wicklund, Anita, 1973 (Box 70)
      Human evolution and Julian Huxley
    - Wickmire, Grant T., 1957-58, 60 (Box 70)
    - Wiedemer, Jean E., 1941 (Box 70)
    - Wiedmann, J., 1964-65 (Box 70)
    - Wieland, G.R., 1924, 26 (Box 70)
      Critique of Wieland's work by GGS
    - Wiggins, Allan A., Jr., 1969 (Box 70)
    - Wiggins, Jim, 1984 (Box 70)
    - Wilcox, Maurice J., 1960 (Box 70)
    - Wilde, Anne, 1974-76 (Box 70)
      Yale University Press, Penguins
    - Wildlife Education Ltd., 1983 (Box 70)
    - Wiley, E.O., 1980 (Box 70)
    - Wiley, John and Sons, Inc., 1955-56, 58-59, 65, 75-76 (Box 70)
    - Wiley, Mary, 1971, 74 (Box 70)
      American Society of Zoologists
    - Wilkens, Horst, 1970 (Box 70)
    - Wilkes, R.E., 1968 (Box 70)
    - Wilkinson, Paul F., 1969 (Box 70)
    - Willem, Pedro, 1941 (Box 70)
    - William Morrow and Co., 1980 (Box 70)
    - Williams, Alwyn, 1959 (Box 70)
      nature of explanation
    - Williams, Coleman S. (Coley), 1929, 31, 33-34, 68, 70, 80 (Box 70)
    - Williams, Curtis A., Jr., 1963-66 (Box 70)
    - Williams, Ernest E., 1954, 77 (Box 70)
    - Williams, G.C., 1979 (Box 70)
    - Williams, Gardner, 1954 (Box 70)
    - Williams, Jay, 1951 (Box 70)
    - Williams, Jesse Lynch, 1929 (Box 70)
    - Williams, Lou (Ms.), 1943 (Box 70)
    - Williams, Marie V.V., 1964-65 (Box 70)
    - Williams, Michael E., 1970 (Box 70)
    - Williams, Richard B., 1966 (Box 70)
    - Williams, S. Culver, 1965 (Box 70)
    - Williams, Thomas E., 1975 (Box 70)
    - Williamson, A.A., 1960 (Box 70)
    - Williamson, Charles O., 1966-67 (Box 70)
    - Williamson, Francis S.L., 1968 (Box 70)
    - Willink, Abraham, 1958 (Box 70)
    - Wilman, M., 1930 (Box 70)
    - Wilson, Allan, 1963, 68, 73-74 (Box 71)
    - Wilson, Don E., 1971 (Box 71)
    - Wilson, Edward O., 1962-67, 71-72, 78, 81-82, 84 (Box 71)
    - Wilson, Edwin B., 1960 (Box 71)
    - Wilson, Edwin H., 1973 (Box 71)
      Humanist Manifesto II
    - Wilson, Graham, 1982 (Box 71)
    - Wilson, Grove, 1934 (Box 71)
    - Wilson, John A., 1937, 40, 53-54, 58, 64-65, 73-75 (Box 71)
    - Wilson, John W., III, 1969-70, 73 (Box 71)
    - Wilson, Robert W., 1937, 53, 55-56, 59, 61, 66, 72-74 (Box 71)
    - Wilson, Stephen Jay, 1965 (Box 71)
    - Wilson, Thomas J., 1968 (Box 71)
      Atheneum Publishers, publication of GGS journals
    - Wind, J., 1974 (Box 71)
    - Winder, C. Gordon, 1978-84 (Box 71)
      Creationism and Gish
    - Windhausen, Rodolfo A., 1979-80 (Box 71)
    - Wing, Willis Kingsley, 1934, 38-40, 46, 57, 59, 60 (Box 71)
    - Winkelmann, R.K., 1964 (Box 71)
    - Winslow, John H., 1972, 74 (Box 71)
      Doubleday and Company
    - Winslow, Richard K., 1959 (Box 71)
    - Winston, Paul W., 1975 (Box 71)
    - Winthrop, John, 1959 (Box 71)
    - Winthrop-Rogers, 1977 (Box 71)
    - Wisconsin, University of (Milwaukee), 1961-62 (Box 71)
    - Wisconsin, University of (Press), 1976 (Box 71)
    - Wisden, Marigold, 1976-77 (Box 71)
      Darjeeling Club Ltd.
    - Wisherd, Maude E., 1941 (Box 71)
    - Wissenschaftliche Buchgesellschaft, 1969-72 (Box 71)
    - Wissler, Clark, 1931, 38-41 (Box 71)
    - Withers, Joan C., 1983-84 (Box 71)
    - Wittenberg, Jonathan B., 1963-64 (Box 71)
    - Wittlin, Alma S., 1973 (Box 71)
    - Wodzicki, K., 1952 (Box 71)
    - Wolf, Irvin S., 1962 (Box 71)
    - Wolf, John, 1983 (Box 71)
    - Wolf, Patricia, 1981 (Box 71)
    - Wolfe, Stephen L., 1976 (Box 71)
    - Wolff, Harold G., 1960 (Box 71)
    - Wolff, Ronald G., 1982-83 (Box 71)
    - Wolfson, Albert, 1957 (Box 71)
    - Wolsan, Mieczylaw, 1984 (Box 71)
    - Wong, Clara E., 1963 (Box 71)
    - Wood, Albert Elmer, 1932, 1936, 1947, 1949, 1954-1962, 1968-1974, 1982, 1984 (Box 71)
    - Wood, Donald, 1962 (Box 71)
    - Wood, F.G., 1970-71 (Box 71)
    - Wood, Gordon D., II, 1972 (Box 71)
    - Wood, Herbert H., 1966 (Box 71)
      Kansas Regional Council for Higher Education
    - Wood, Horace E. and Florence P., 1926-1980; 2 folders (Box 71)
      Biographical and personal data; Harvard University -- Museum of Comparative Zoology; Leakey, Louis Seymour Bazett; National Academy of Sciences; Paleontology; Patterson, Bryan; Political issues -- Animal welfare; Publication; Recommendations; Requests for reprints; Research support; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Zoology; Zoology -- Classification; Zoology -- Nomenclature
    - Wood, Paul A., 1965 (Box 71)
    - Wood, Raymond A., 1958 (Box 71)
    - Wood, Roger, 1966, 68, 73 (Box 71)
    - Wood, Sherwin F., 1962 (Box 71)
    - Wood, Thurston, 1959-60 (Box 71)
    - Wood, William J., 1971-72 (Box 71)
      Stocks
    - Woodall, Donald S., II, 1970 (Box 71)
    - Woodburne, Michael O., 1972, 76, 82 (Box 71)
    - Woodmansee, Ray B., 1967 (Box 71)
    - Woodring, Wendell P., 1940, 52, 60, 80, 82 (Box 71)
    - Woodward, Arthur Smith and Maud, 1927-28, 32-33, 35-38, 40, 50, 58 (Box 71)
    - Woodward, Herbert N., 1972 (Box 71)
    - Woodward, Lee A., 1971 (Box 71)
      University of New Mexico
    - Woodward, W. Kenneth, 1952 (Box 71)
    - Woodwell, G.M., 1968-69 (Box 71)
    - Woodworth's Book Store, 1941 (Box 71)
    - World Book Encyclopedia, 1957 (Box 71)
    - World Scope Encyclopedia, 1948 (Box 71)
    - Worth Publishers, 1966 (Box 72)
    - Worthley, Donald G., 1953 (Box 72)
    - Wrenn, Robert L., 1984 (Box 72)
    - Wright, Fred E., 1941 (Box 72)
    - Wright, G. Wilfred, 1964 (Box 72)
    - Wright, Margaret R., 1960 (Box 72)
      Vasser College
    - Wright, Marshall, 1973-74 (Box 72)
    - Wright, Nelda, 1942, 67 (Box 72)
    - Wright, Sewall, 1945 (Box 72)
    - Wright, W.D., 1960 (Box 72)
    - Wrigley, G.M., 1941 (Box 72)
      American Geolographical Society
    - Wycoff, Charles C., 1971 (Box 72)
    - Wylde, Hildegarde Howard, 1961 (Box 72)
    - Wyman, Leland C., 1940 (Box 72)
    - Wynn-Edwards, V.C., 1947 (Box 72)
    - Wyoming, University of, 1971 (Box 72)
    - Xerox Individualized Publishing, 1974 (Box 72)
    - Yablokov, Alexey V., 1967-70, 72, 76, 80 (Box 72)
    - Yadagiri, P., 1977-78 (Box 72)
    - Yale Review, 1947-52 (Box 72)
    - Yale University, 1922, 24-32, 35, 50, 53, 61-68, 72-73 (Box 72)
      Dana Club
    - Yale University (Terry Lectures), 1947-48 (Box 72)
    - Yale University Press (Behavior and Evolution), 1956-59, 63, 69 (Box 72)
    - Yale University Press (Concessions to the Improbable), 1976-78, 82 (Box 72)
    - Yale University Press (Life in the Past), 1952-56, 59, 67-70, 77, 83 (Box 72)
    - Yale University Press (Meaning of Evolution), 1949-57, 59, 69, 71-72, 75, 78-79 (Box 72)
    - Yale University Press (Meaning of Evolution, reaction), 1941-61, 65 (Box 73)
    - Yale University Press (Miscellany), 1928-29, 39, 50-52, 64, 67-69, 77-78, 83 (Box 73)
    - Yale University Press (Penguins), 1974-79 (Box 73)
    - Yale University Press (Splendid Isolation & Discoverers Lost World), 1980-84 (Box 73)
    - Yamamoto, Kaoru, 1973 (Box 73)
    - Ybarra, Emilio Antonio, 1962-63, 73 (Box 73)
    - Yeckes, Cliff, 1979 (Box 73)
    - Yensen, Nicholas P., 1974 (Box 73)
    - Yochelson, Ellis L., 1958, 61, 71, 82-83 (Box 73)
      History of Earth Sciences Society
    - Yoken, Melvin B., 1971, 73, 77, 82-83 (Box 73)
    - York University, 1966 (Box 73)
    - Youden, W.J., 1948 (Box 73)
    - Young, Chung-chien, 1939, 67, 72-75, 78 (Box 73)
      Bibliography on Tritylodontoidea, 39
    - Young, Clem, 1939 (Box 73)
    - Young, J.Z., 1950-51, 58, 62, 80 (Box 73)
    - Young, R.A., 1964 (Box 73)
    - Yuhas, Sharon, 1965 (Box 73)
    - Zaborsky, Nitra Stefan, 1964 (Box 73)
    - Zahl, Paul A., 1976 (Box 73)
    - Zangerl, Rainer, 1948, 50, 60 (Box 73)
    - Zapfe, Helmuth, 1980, 82 (Box 73)
    - Zappler, Georg, 1964 (Box 73)
    - Zaunick, Rudolph, 1960 (Box 73)
    - Zdansky, Otto, 1938 (Box 73)
    - Zeeman, Diane, 1980 (Box 73)
      Pergamon Press, Why and How
    - Zeeman, Maurice, 1980 (Box 73)
    - Zeiss, Carl, Inc., 1938-39 (Box 73)
    - Zeitschrift Des Kolner Zoo, 1976 (Box 73)
    - Zetti, Jorge, 1970 (Box 73)
    - Zeuner, F.E., 1948 (Box 73)
    - Zheng, Jia-jian, 1979 (Box 73)
    - Zhou, Mingzhen, 1982-83 (Box 73)
    - Zidek, Jiri, 1982 (Box 73)
      Journal of Vertebrate Paleontology
    - Zimmer, John T., 1936 (Box 73)
    - Zimmerman, Elwood C., 1940, 42-43, 46, 58, 60, 74 (Box 73)
    - Zimmerman, W., 1959 (Box 73)
    - Zindler, Frank R., 1970 (Box 73)
      American International School
    - Zingg, Robert Mowry, 1933-34 (Box 73)
    - Zinn, Donald J., 1967 (Box 73)
    - Zinn, Oswald J., 1943 (Box 73)
    - Zinsmeister, William J., 1975 (Box 73)
    - Zirkle, Conway, 1951, 54, 61 (Box 73)
    - Zoological Society of London, 1948-50, 56-57, 71, 73, 75 (Box 73)
    - Zuberi, A.K., 1964 (Box 73)
    - Zubrow, Ezra, 1968 (Box 73)
    - Zuck, Robert K., 1961 (Box 73)
    - Zuckerkandl, Emile, 1974 (Box 73)
    - Zuckerman, Solly, 1947, 49, 56, 62, 68, 74 (Box 73)
    - Zuidema, Harry P., 1977-78 (Box 73)
      Creationism at Michigan State
    - Zweifel, Richard G., 1971 (Box 73)
  - Series II. Published Works, 1929-1984; 3 linear feet (Box 74-79)
    Manuscripts, typed carbons, and reprints of published books and articles by Simpson. They are arranged alphabetically by title. (A copy of Simpson's bibliography may be found in Series IX.) Of special note in this series is the manuscript version of Simpson's autobiography, Concession to the Improbable. Many of these works are partial manuscripts or sections of a work, such as the introduction, preface, or index. Book reviews of Simpson's publications are filed in this series under the title of the work. Illustrations from published works may be found in Series IV Research Notes, filed under the title of the publication and/or subject of the work. (See the folder listing on page 8.)
    - Agassiz: end of an era (review of Intelligence of Louis Agassiz), 1964 (Box 74)
    - Ameghinos' localities for early Cenozoic mammals in Patagonia, the, 1967 (Box 74)
    - American Mesozoic Mammalia, 1929 (Box 74)
    - Anatomie et biologie des rhinogrades (review of), 1963 (Box 74)
    - Attending marvels (reviews of), 1934 (Box 74)
    - Australian fossil penguins with remarks on penguin evolution and distribution, 1957 (Box 74)
    - Autobiology, 1982 (Box 74)
    - Beginning of the age of mammals in South America (Part 2), the, 1967; 17 folders (Box 74)
      Manuscript.
    - Beginning of the age of mammals in South America (Part 2), the, 1967 (Box 75)
      Carbon copies.
    - Behavior and evolution (review of), 1958 (Box 75)
    - Biological sciences, 1965 (Box 75)
    - Biology and man, 1969 (Box 75)
    - Biology and the public good, 1967 (Box 75)
    - Book of Darwin, the, 1983 (Box 75-76)
    - Case history of a scientific news story, the, 1940 (Box 76)
    - Charles Darwin, 1974 (Box 76)
    - Compleat palaeontologist?, the, 1976 (Box 76)
    - Concession to the improbable, an unconventional autobiography, 1978 (Box 76)
    - Concluding remarks: Mesozoic mammals revisited, 1971 (Box 76)
    - Continental tertiary time chart, a, 1947 (Box 76)
    - Crisis in biology, the, 1967 (Box 76)
    - Discoverers of the lost world, an account of some of those who brought back to life South American mammals long buried in abyss of time, 1984 (Box 77)
    - End of an era in biology, 1965 (Box 77)
    - Evolution and geography (review of), 1953 (Box 77)
    - Evolution of the horse family, 1973 (Box 77)
    - Fossil mammals from the Cenozoic of Acre, Brazil, 1981 (Box 77)
    - Fossil penguin from the late Cenozoic in South Africa, 1971 (Box 77)
    - Fossils and the history of life, 1983 (Box 77)
    - Granger, Walter (Biography in Dictionary of American Biography), 1972 (Box 77)
    - Historical science, 1963 (Box 77)
    - Historical zoogeography of Australian mammals, 1961 (Box 77)
    - History of marsupials, 1977 (Box 77)
    - Horses (index only), 1951 (Box 77)
    - Horses (preface to Japanese version), 1979 (Box 77)
    - Lamarck, Darwin, and Butler, three approaches to evolution in the 19th century, 1961 (Box 78)
    - Life of the past (reviews of), 1953 (Box 78)
    - Logbook for Grace (introduction only), 1965 (Box 78)
    - Major features of evolution (reviews of), 1953 (Box 78)
    - Mammals and cryptozoology, 1984 (Box 78)
    - Man's evolutionary future, 1960 (Box 78)
    - Meaning of evolution (reviews of), 1949 (Box 78)
    - Meaning of evolution (revised edition), 1967 (Box 78)
    - Memorial to Horace Elmer Wood, 1977 (Box 78)
    - Miocene penguins from Victoria, Australia, and Chubut, Argentina, 1970 (Box 78)
    - New heaven and a new earth and a new man, a, 1977 (Box 78)
    - New record of euceratherium or preptoceras (extinct Bovidae) in New Mexico, a, 1963 (Box 78)